#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/shane-dean (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

R programming Spreadsheets Data Visualization

### Certifications

Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere

Prepare Data for Exploration
Analyze Data to Answer Questions
Data Analysis with R Programming
Querying Databases Using SQL
SELECT statement

# **Shane Dean**

Data Analyst | SQL | R | Ocean lover | Learning Python Eugene, Oregon, United States

## Summary

In October of 2023, I began my journey in finding a new career path in data analytics. I have recently completed my Google Data Analytics certification through Merit America, where I built up the required basics in essential skills such as R programming, SQL, and Tableau. I am ready to start a new chapter in my life using the skills being fostered in this course to enter into a data analytics role where I can continue to learn and grow.

My present passion for data analytics is fortified by the past skills I have built up over my working career. My previous work experiences have been mostly focused in Labor focused industries. Through these, I have developed a strong work ethic and strong learning ability when it comes to new skills being taught to me. Through my past as a scuba instructor I learned how to more easily disseminate complex information at a simpler level. These skills have allowed me to excel at tasks given to me through my employment opportunities.

## Experience

Enchanted Job Seeker Studio
Junior Data Analyst
January 2024 - Present (1 year 7 months)
United States

Volunteering to navigate the changes in the digital world that are impacting their search for jobs

Ninkasi Brewing
Packager

July 2023 - September 2023 (3 months)

Assisted with high daily production requirements, with tasks ranging from stacking pallets, to observing and assisting certain components of the line to achieve a smooth work flow.

Sailfish Brewing Company
Packager
June 2022 - June 2023 (1 year 1 month)
Fort Pierce, Florida, United States

Sanitized and connected all parts and hoses necessary for daily production run, Assisted Line Lead with Canning Line start up and tuning to ensure optimal fill levels of product, as well as timely fill rates up to 50 cans a minute. Stack pallets to Distribution requirements. Filled 1/6 barrel and 1/2 barrel kegs for distribution, as well as in house sale.

Wood N Things
Carpenter
October 2021 - May 2022 (8 months)
Port St Lucie, Florida, United States

## Education

Merit America

Google Data Analytics, Data Processing · (October 2023 - February 2024)